# **Brandon Shurick**

Seattle, WA • +1.206.355.1535 • brandon.shurick@gmail.com • linkedin.com/in/bshurick • brandonshurick.com

### **SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS**

A motivated analytics professional, who recently completed a Master of Information and Data Science from UC Berkeley, with experience utilizing statistical methods and machine learning to extract meaningful insights and create data products from large amounts of customer and operational data.

## **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

# TRAVELBIRD [AMSTERDAM] Senior BI Engineer (Data Scientist)

June 2015 - June 2016

- Created and deployed to production collaborative filtering algorithm using Apache Spark (with proven increases in email CTR 30%+ and order conversion 200%+)
- Developed fully-automated e-mail testing solution using Python and Vertica, splitting test and control groups and evaluating results across relevant covariates with statistical testing in Tableau dashboard
- Created dashboards for analysis of product AB tests and e-mail experiments
- Developed product-product similarity matrix which is utilized by the production website

# WESTWING GROUP GMBH [MUNICH] Senior DWH/BI Developer

July 2014 - May 2015

- Measured primary contributors to churn and assisted with development company strategy for increasing engagement
- Deployed Vertica data warehouse, migrated from legacy MySQL system
- Automated and improved quality of many legacy Excel-based data management and reporting systems, replacing with web interfaces or Tableau dashboards

# T-MOBILE USA [SEATTLE] Senior Engineer, Technology Product Development

May 2012 - June 2014

- Managed Hadoop cluster to analyze handset performance data
- Created analytical models and dashboards for exploring and analyze handset performance
- Designed mobile software product requirements, led product development via managed software development vendor
- Presented product prototypes to top management to secure program funding

### Senior Business Analyst, Customer Care Finance

July 2010 - May 2012

- Analyzed customer call details and customer care agent performance metrics to uncover insights for management team
- Presented discoveries to management team in clear and concise format to assist decision making
- Measured performance of customer care projects and facilitated development of business cases to assist budgeting team with cost-reduction measures

## **Brandon Shurick**

Seattle, WA • +1.206.355.1535 • brandon.shurick@gmail.com • linkedin.com/in/bshurick • brandonshurick.com

### **TECHNICAL TOOLSET**

SQL	Python SciPy Stack	Django (Web)	Apache Spark	D3.js
Python	R	MapReduce / MRjob	NoSQL	Gephi

### **EDUCATION**

## **UNIVERSITY OF CALIFORNIA [BERKELEY]**

**January 2015 - August 2016** 

## Master of Information and Data Science (MIDS)

**Coursework:** Storing and Retrieving Data, Experiments and Causal Inference, Applied Machine Learning, Research Design & Applications for Data Analysis, Exploring and Analyzing Data, Fundamentals of Linear Algebra, Fundamentals of Data Structures and Algorithms, Visualizing and Communicating Data, Machine Learning at Scale, Applied Regression and Time Series Analysis, Capstone Course

## UNIVERSITY OF WASHINGTON [SEATTLE]

September 2004 - June 2008

**Bachelor of Arts in Business Administration** with formal options in Finance & Information Systems *Accolades*: Annual Dean's List 2007-2008

### **PROJECTS**

- Data Visualization: Moral Reflection for a Better World (<u>moralworldviews.info</u>)
- Data Storage & Retrieval: Streaming Twitter Storage (<a href="http://goo.gl/U3yZvq">http://goo.gl/U3yZvq</a>)
- Machine Learning at Scale: Criteo Ad Prediction in Apache Spark (http://goo.gl/N6VUYi)
- Field Experiment: Video or Text Math Education (<a href="https://goo.gl/e0NfZZ">https://goo.gl/e0NfZZ</a>)
- MIDS Capstone Project (<a href="http://goaltick.info">http://goaltick.info</a>)